Austin Buhler

New York City | (949) 614-6943 | austinbuhler@gmail.com | GitHub | Blog | LinkedIn

Full Stack Software Developer

Software engineer experienced in JavaScript, React and Ruby on Rails with a background in corporate finance. Analytical, strategically minded leader with a demonstrated ability of driving business objectives into results. Efficient and resourceful problem solver with an innate curiosity and an entrepreneurial spirit who thrives in a fast-paced team environment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript | React | Redux | Ruby | Rails | Power BI | DAX | SQL | EDI | XML | Dynamics NAV | Quickbooks | Hyperion | TM1

PROJECTS

ProjectSocial - FrontEnd | BackEnd | Website

A social app connecting New Yorkers by enabling them to host and attend events at public parks in their local neighborhood. This is a Single-Page Application built with React/Redux, PostgreSQL and a RESTful Rails API.

- Utilized React Hooks and Redux for state management as well as React Router for Client-Side Routing
- Normalized store shape to ensure a single-source of truth and increased application performance
- Integrated parks' data from NYC's Open Data Portal with Google Maps API to plot all public parks and their activities
- Leveraged WebSockets to ensure a real-time event news feed for seamless user communication and coordination
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side

Candle Crush - FrontEnd | BackEnd

An e-commerce site for high-end candles, built with a Rails API & React front-end. A Single-Page Application leveraging React Router for Client-Side Routing.

- Developed RESTful routes with endpoints to process product returns and manage real-time inventory levels
- Enabled users to leave ratings and reviews for individual products to increase customer engagement and visibility
- Implemented role-based user experiences for both vendors and consumers with JWT and BCrypt authentication

Stonks.js - FrontEnd | BackEnd

A financial markets (ie: stocks and company news) tracking application, built with a Rails API and Vanilla JS front-end.

- Served up real-time stock quotes and news articles with IEX Cloud's API for user's favorite companies
- Aggregated historical pricing information with Chart.js to provide a clean and simple interface for trend analysis
- Designed an autocomplete search feature to lookup publicly trading companies by name or ticker symbol

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Siggi's Dairy

Senior Manager, FP&A

New York, NY Apr 2020 – Aug 2020

- Prepared and led monthly financial presentations delivering actionable insights and driving strategic decisions alongside key internal and external stakeholders
- Developed and actively managed rolling forecast, identifying key risks and opportunities to budget financials
 Manager, FP&A

 Apr 2019 Mar 2020
 - Spearheaded \$200MM+ annual budget and operating plan, facilitating cross-functional collaboration
 - Served as ERP Systems Manager, ensuring data integrity, improving reports/processes and actively managing 50+ EDI trading partners
 - Collaborated with intercompany partners and external consultants to ensure all system functional requirements were met as part of freight consolidation project leading to \$5MM+ in savings

Senior Financial Analyst

Jan 2018 – Mar 2019

- Drove and executed financial reporting integration efforts into Hyperion and TM1 following international acquisition
- Designed and implemented a fully automated Daily Sales Dashboard, increasing efficiency and enabling real-time analysis of business trends and KPIs

Financial Analyst

Aug 2016 – Dec 2017

- Managed monthly COGS analysis, inventory reconciliation & valuation with our 3PL provider and quarterly co-manufacturer audits that led to \$150K+ in rebates
- Supported transition from Quickbooks to Microsoft NAV serving as the order-to-cash subject matter expert

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

New York, NY Dec 2020

Software Engineering Immersive; Javascript, React, Ruby on Rails

Southern Methodist University, Cox School of Business

Dallas, TX

Bachelor of Business Administration. Finance

May 2016